NYSUT Audio-Visual Materials 6174 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
NYSUT Audio-Visual Materials
1969-2005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)
6174 AV
18.94 cubic feet
18.9 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
7164231
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 15, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 24, 2016
Biographical / Historical
New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) was created in 1972 by the merger of the New York State Teachers Association (NYSTA) and the United Teachers of New York (UTNY). NYSTA had been affiliated with the National Education Association (NEA), and UTNY with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). UTNY was the statewide organization whose United Federation of Teachers (UFT), led by Albert Shanker, was the predominant teachers' union in New York City. In joining with United Teachers and affiliating with the AFT, NYSUT also became a member union of the AFL-CIO.
In 1976, NYSUT voted to disaffiliate with the NEA. Some locals left NYSUT and created the NYEA (New York Educators Association), which became the state affiliate for the NEA. In the early 1980s, NYEA changed its name to NEA-NY.
NYEA/NEA- NY viewed association with the AFL-CIO's industrial unions as undermining the professional image and independence of teachers. The two organizations also differed strongly on aspects of the governance structure, particularly with respect to ethnic minority representation, with NYSUT opposed to mandatory minimums. The rivalry between NYSUT and NYEA/NEA-NY in organizing new locals expended a great deal of resources for both labor organizations.
While competition with NYEA/NEA-NY was a constant focus of NYSUT's organizing efforts for teachers, NYSUT was also organizing college faculty members, nurses, and other non-teaching personnel. Once members were organized, NYSUT continued to advocate for teachers' and other workers' rights through contract support and legal services at the local level and political involvement at the state and federal levels, supporting candidates and legislation that protected funding, due process, and working conditions.
NEA-N Y merged with NYSUT in 2006, by which time NYSUT had grown to more than half a million members, becoming the largest union in New York State.
Scope and Contents
Training tapes and videos on a varietyof topics, 1969-2005, focusing on the 1980s and '90s. Includes speeches and interviews with NYSUT president Tom Hobart, clips from Representative Assemblies, tributes honoring Al Shanker.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6174/017 MB: NYSUT General Officers Memorabilia 6174: NYSUT Records 6174 MB: NYSUT Memorabilia 6174 OH: NYSUT Oral History Interviews 6174 P: NYSUT Photographs 6174 PUBS: NYSUT Publications 6174/001: NYSUT President's Office Files 6174/001 P: NYSUT President's Office Photographs 6174/002: NYSUT Vice President's Office files 6174/003: NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services. Files 6174/004: NYSUT Field Services Department Files 6174/004 AV: NYSUT Field Services Department Audio-Visual Material 6174/005: NYSUT Legislative Department Files 6174/006: NYSUT Public Relations Department Files 6174/007: NYSUT New York Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education Files 6174/008: NYSUT Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Files 6174/009: NYSUT Teacher Education Conference Board Files 6174/010: NYSUT Convention files 6174/011: NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office Files 6174/012: NYSUT "Teachers United: The Rise of NYSUT" Research Notes 6174/013 AV: NYSUT Representative Assembly (RA) Audio-Visual materials 6174/014: NYSUT Alan Lubin Files 6174/015: NYSUT Boards of Directors Meetings 6174/016: NYSUT Vice-President's Office Maria Neira. Files 6174/017: NYSUT General Officers Records 6174/017 AV: NYSUT General Officers Audio-Visual Materials 6174/017 P: NYSUT General Officers Photographs 6174/018: NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files 6174/019: NYSUT Biography File
Teachers' union -- New York (State); New York State United Teachers
7164231
- Arbitration Training #3, 1 (Box 1)
- Arbitration Video -- 3/27/1989, 2 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Raw Foot -- Tape 1
- Arbitration Video -- 3/27/1989, 3 (Box 1)
  Raw Footage -- Original -- Tape 1
- Arbitration Training Window Dub, 4 (Box 1)
  Tapes #1, #2, #3
- Arbitration Training: A Case of Proper Step Placement, 1989; 5 (Box 1)
  Part B & C - Day 1; Prototype: Work in Progress 10/1989
- Arbitration Training 2-B: A Case of Proper Step Placement, 1989; 6 (Box 1)
  Part B & C - Day 2; Prototype: Work in Progress - 10/1989 -- Edit Master
- Arbitration Training 2: A Case of Proper Step Placement, 1989; 7 (Box 1)
  Part B & C - Day 2 -- Prototype: Work in Progress -- 10/1989
- Arbitration Video -- 3/27/1989, 8 (Box 1)
  Raw Footage -- Original -- Tape 2
- Arbitration Video -- 3/27/1989, 9 (Box 1)
  Raw Foot -- Tape 2
- Arbitration Training #2 - Jeff Cassidy, 10 (Box 1)
- Arbitration Training #1 - Jeff Cassidy; Bill Seams, 11 (Box 1)
- NYSUT -- 2003 RA; Session 1, 6 (Box 2)
- NYSUT -- 2003 RA -- Session 3B, 7 (Box 2)
- NYSUT -- 2003 RA -- Session 3A, 8 (Box 2)
- A Proud Tradition -- AFT: A Union of Professionals, 9 (Box 2)
- NYSUT - "2004 RA", 10 (Box 2)
  Tape 1 of 3
- NYSUT -- "2004 RA", 11 (Box 2)
  Tape 3 of 3
- NYSUT -- "2004 RA", 12 (Box 2)
  Tape 2 of 3
- AFT and NYSUT: The Rebirth of Democracy, 2005; 13 (Box 2)
  7/27/2005
- 1990 Solidarity Video - "Road to Democracy", 2005; 14 (Box 2)
  AFT QuEST Conference 2005
- March Segment Rough cut, 2003; 15 (Box 2)
  Public Education Rally -- May 3, 2003
- NOW with Bill Moyers, 2004; 16 (Box 2)
  "Criminalizing Dissent" -- 2/27/2004
- NYSUT -- 2003 RA -- Session 4B, 17 (Box 2)
- NYSUT -- 2003 RA -- Session 4A, 18 (Box 2)
- Tuition Tax Credit Radio Spots, 19 (Box 2)
- NYSUT - Albany Legal -- Case log; Decision log; Warehouse list (Box 3)
  - NYSUT - Albany Legal -- Case log; Decision log; Warehouse list, 1 (Box 3)
- Richard Rowley Address, (Aug. 26, 1970); Emanuel Kafka, 1 (Box 4)
  Oswego W.S. (at Platsborough) Aug. 1970
- Operation Feedback, 1970; 2 (Box 4)
  Syracuse, NY -- April 29, 1970 -- Mr. Kafka and Area HS Students
- Emanuel Kafka interviews in North Eastern Zone (Jan. 20(?), 1969), 3 (Box 4)
  Insight - pt. 1-4; WPTZ - News Interview; Shelia Cluff show was not aired because of technical difficulties
- New York State Teachers Assn.; Afternoon session, 1971; 4 (Box 4)
  11/08/1971 -- House of Delegates - 4:00 pm - 5:30 pm -- @ Onondaga County War Memorial auditorium. Syracuse, NY -- Very little speaker ID on tape See NYSTA notes & delegate list
- New York State Teachers Assn. - Intro. To Sen. Jackson on side 4; Speech on side 5, 1971; 5 (Box 4)
  11/08/1971 -- House o delegates @ Onondaga County War Memorial Auditorium -- Very little speaker ID on tape - see separate notes
- New York State Teachers Assn., 1971; 6 (Box 4)
  11/09/1971 -- House of Delegates @ Onondaga County War Memorial Auditorium, Syracuse, NY -- Very little speaker ID on tape - for complete ID see NYSTA notes and delegate list
- New York State Teachers Assn.. - 11/08/1971, 7 (Box 4)
  House of Delegates - 9am - 4 pm @ Onondaga County War Memorial Auditorium; Syracuse, New York -- Very little Speaker ID on tape.
- New York State Teachers Assn. -- 11/07/1971, 8 (Box 4)
  House of Delegates @ Onondaga War Memorial Auditorium, Syracuse, NY -- Speaker ID in Steno Book and Delegate List
- West Seneca - Diane Marshuto, 9 (Box 4)
- NYSUT - Revised - 7/7/1997, 10 (Box 4)
  V.O.'s only
- Wrath of Grapes Boycott; United Farm Workers of America, AFL-CIO --- Fast for Life, 11 (Box 4)
- NYSUT Interviews -- 2/3/1995, 12 (Box 4)
  Window dubs of 6 original Beta SP Cassettes
- NYSUT - "Teacher of the Year V.O.", 13 (Box 4)
- NYSUT Candids, 14 (Box 4)
  rev.
- Coalition on Economic priorities, 15 (Box 4)
  904-02
- Coalition on Economic Priorities, 16 (Box 4)
  904-01
- Grandville Rally, 17 (Box 4)
- NYSUT - Chavez -- 3/11/1989, 18 (Box 4)
  tape 1
- Toni Cortese Testimony - Senate Standing Committee, 19 (Box 4)
  Hearing -- NYS Board of Regents reappointment/candidates
- Task Force, 20 (Box 4)
- Task Force, 21 (Box 4)
- Al Shanker's speech at Statewide in-service conference - Desmond Americana, Albany, 1989; 1 (Box 5)
  12/4/1989 -- Tape 72-948-02
- NYSUT Network, 2 (Box 5)
  A visual overview of the NYSUT booklet "Programs Services Publications" outlining the benefits offered to the organization's membership -- MASTER
- Public Policy in an Aging Society, 1984; 3 (Box 5)
  tape 1 of 2 --- CBS Sunday Morning - Cover Story - Sandy Bliss (Utica NYSUT); Labor operation for Mondale in Dem. 4/3/1984 Primary
- News ABC - Sept. 4, Ch. 10; Albany, WTEN, 1984; 4 (Box 5)
  schools, interviews -- Tom Hobart - Ch. 10 News - 11:00 Sept. 4, 1984
- Katze NATPE Preview, 5 (Box 5)
- Westchester Teachers, 6 (Box 5)
- Child Labor Laws and Their Impact on Education, 7 (Box 5)
  featuring Tom Hobart O/A WNYT - TV-13, Albany, NY // Local TV station interviews NYSUT's President to get his views on child labor laws and how they effect our children's education
- Al Shanker's speech Statewide in-service Conf., 1989; 8 (Box 5)
  12/4/1989 at Desmond Americana -- Albany, NY --- MASTER
- Al Shanker's speech at Statewide in-service conf., 1989; 9 (Box 5)
  12/4/1989 -- Desmond Americana, Albany -- MASTER
- Al Shanker's speech at Statewide in-service conference, 1989; 10 (Box 5)
  Desmond Americana, Albany -- 12/4/1989 --- MASTER
- New York State United Teaches "Future", 11 (Box 5)
  NY30-170-1
- Veterans Leadership Program Presentation Tape, 12 (Box 5)
- Al Shanker's speech at Statewide in-service conference, 1989; 1 (Box 6)
  Desmond Americana, Albany -- 12/4/1989 -- MASTER -- tape 72-948- 01
- Al Shanker's speech at Statewide in-service conference, 1989; 2 (Box 6)
  Desmond Americana, Albany -- 12/4/1989 -- MASTER -- Tape 72-948- 03
- Al Shanker's conference at Statewide in-service conference, 1989; 3 (Box 6)
  Desmond Americana, Albany -- 12/4/1989 -- MASTER -- tape 72- 948-04
- Martin Luther King Jr., 4 (Box 6)
  Pres. - starring: Tom Hobart
- PEF - Making union history, 5 (Box 6)
- P/PV "Step", 6 (Box 6)
- Inside your schools reforms in Public Education Program #505 -- NYSUT, 7 (Box 6)
- Maureen, Anderson & Conway -- "To Dream", 8 (Box 6)
- The Citizen Bee, 1989; 9 (Box 6)
- Candids - NYSUT -- 1998, 10 (Box 6)
- Session 3 - Sat. Morning -- Green, Ferraro, McLaughlin, 11 (Box 6)
- 1985 NYSUT - Radio Print TV Ads - "What the Union Means to Me", 12 (Box 6)
- Tom Hobart's interview at Democratic Convention, NYC -, 1992; 13 (Box 6)
  noon news by WRGB -- 7/14/1992
- Children in crisis -, 1992; 14 (Box 6)
  AFT video news release -- 2/11/1992
- NYSUT - 1997 RA -- V.P. Al Gore, 15 (Box 6)
  3 copies
- Clips from profile of profession - NYSUT, 1 (Box 7)
- NYSUT: A voice for the future, 2 (Box 7)
- Nat'l Certification - Gen. Session 2, 3 (Box 7)
  4-6 - Fri.
- NYSUT VO - " The Lost Line", 1997; 4 (Box 7)
  4/24/1997
- NYSUT: A voice for the future, 5 (Box 7)
- Tape 6 -- NYSUT, 6 (Box 7)
  11-5
- NYSUT - V.O.'s, 1997; 7 (Box 7)
  Anniversary Overview; Standards; Leaders of the PAC; SRP of the year (4/16/1997)
- NYSUT - 1-view, 8 (Box 7)
  Selects -- "Turn Point"
- Teacher Award, 9 (Box 7)
  Gen. Session 3 -- Sat. 9-12
- NYSUT: A voice for the future, 10 (Box 7)
  MASTER
- Tom Hobart -, 1989; 11 (Box 7)
  Channel 6 -- April 5, 1989 (73-913)
- Press Conf. @ NYSUT, 12 (Box 7)
  tape 1 (cut aways)
- Hobart Mid-day News, 13 (Box 7)
  Liz Bishop
- NYSUT Shoot, 1995; 14 (Box 7)
  Western, NY -- 11/28 and 11/29/1995
- Segment with Tom Hobart on News in Plattsburgh, 15 (Box 7)
- Workshops SRP, 16 (Box 7)
  include a vote COPE Session, many XCU hands
- NYSUT Shoot, 1995; 17 (Box 7)
  Western, NY -- 11.28 and 11/29/1995
- Education Affair Programs, 1996; 18 (Box 7)
  No. 1996
- The U.F.T. Story, 19 (Box 7)
- Unlabelled, 1 (Box 8)
- Vote/COPE, 1995; 2 (Box 8)
  roll 5 -- revised 2/26/1995 (back up)
- NYSUT 1996, 3 (Box 8)
  Selects - tape 2 (6/13/1996)
- NYSUT Scrohls 1-4, 4 (Box 8)
  Lessons in life; Endorsements; Journalism; Community Service -- Meeting Logo "Quiet Please"
- NYSUT -- 1996, 5 (Box 8)
  Interview source
- NYSUT - 1996 Selects, 6 (Box 8)
  tape 1 of 3
- NYSUT -- 1996 Selects, 7 (Box 8)
  6/13/1996 -- tape 1
- NYSUT -- 1996 -- Selects, 8 (Box 8)
  6/13/1996
- Improving the climate for Public Education, 9 (Box 8)
  Rev. w/Local id mono mix for projection
- NYSUT #8 - Gates Chilli, 10 (Box 8)
  11/28
- NYSUT, 1996; 11 (Box 8)
  1996 Interview Service
- NYSUT --, 1996; 12 (Box 8)
  1996 Secrets -- 6/13/1996
- NYSUT - 11/5/1996, 13 (Box 8)
  New York, NY
- NYSUT -- 11/5/1996, 14 (Box 8)
- NYSUT -- 1996 -- Selects, 15 (Box 8)
- Albert Shanker Tribute, 16 (Box 8)
- American Federation of Teachers - "Al Shanker Tribute", 1997; 17 (Box 8)
  4/3/1997 ---
- Tape -- 71 2 - 71, 18 (Box 8)
  not much labeling
- Roundtable, 1988; 19 (Box 8)
  5/9/1988
- Second half of memorial service - April 9, 1997, 20 (Box 8)
  AFT Shanker Memorial Service Lisner Auditorium -- Switched Program tape 5
- NYSUT 1996, 1 (Box 9)
  New York -- 11/5/1996 - Tape 2 - Joyce James; Danny Feldman
- NYSUT - 1996, 2 (Box 9)
  New York 11/5 -- Tape 1
- NYSUT - 1996, 3 (Box 9)
  Selects - Tape 3 -- 6/13/1996
- NYSUT - 1996, 4 (Box 9)
  Selects
- Diane Marshulo, 5 (Box 9)
  West Seneca Standards
- NYSUT - 1996, 6 (Box 9)
  Selects - (tape 2 of 3)
- American Federation of Teachers -- "Al Shanker Tribute Video" with Lower 3rd's and Credits, 1997; 7 (Box 9)
  Short version -- 4/17/1997
- NYSUT - 1996 -- New York 11/5/1996, 8 (Box 9)
  Tape 4 -- Leo Casey
- NYSUT -- 1996 -- New York 11/5/1996, 9 (Box 9)
  Tape 3 -- Danny Feldman
- NYSUT Compile video, 10 (Box 9)
- NASSAU Compile, 11 (Box 9)
- No covers R3 and R5, 12 (Box 9)
  West Seneca
- Second Half of Memorial Service - April 9, 1997, 13 (Box 9)
  AFT Shanker Memorial Service Lisner Auditorium; ISO Camera Guest Speakers tape 6
- Children's Village - tape 3, 14 (Box 9)
- Carl Megal, 15 (Box 9)
- Carl Megal - Speech #2, 16 (Box 9)
  530-21
- Carl Megal Speech, 17 (Box 9)
  530-24
- NYSUT Shoot, 1995; 18 (Box 9)
  Western, NY -- 11/28, 11/29/1995
- GE Power Systems - "I feel the power today", 1998; 1 (Box 10)
  2/9/1998
- Children's village, 2 (Box 10)
  tape 3
- LCI Demo Field Interviews - Peer Groups, 3 (Box 10)
- Excellent Cadavers, 4 (Box 10)
  HBO movie -- American Federation of Teachers
- Vote Cope 1999, 5 (Box 10)
- United Technologies 1999 theme opener, 6 (Box 10)
- Light and Power Capabilities Demo, 7 (Box 10)
- Light and Power Communications Meetings Demo, 8 (Box 10)
- An evening with George Mitchell, 9 (Box 10)
- Carl Megal - #2 Interview, 10 (Box 10)
  530-26
- Tom Hobart Utica TV, 11 (Box 10)
- Challenge - Tom Hobart -- "The 4 R's", 12 (Box 10)
- Tom Hobart - Channel 10 News - "Teachers with Foreign Accents", 1992; 13 (Box 10)
  7/7/1992
- Carl Megal, 14 (Box 10)
  42-570
- Tom Hobart's Interview at Democratic Convention, NYC, 1992; 15 (Box 10)
  Noon News by WRGB -- 7/14/1992
- WDCO Presents the American Teacher Awards 1998, 16 (Box 10)
  Teachers Tom Porton and Myra Dietz
- NYSUT -- 11/9/1995, 1 (Box 11)
  #04 -- Ray Samson; John Sole
- NYSUT - Albany -- 11/9/1995, 2 (Box 11)
  #03 - Mike Foley; Sal Fiordimalva; Mark Leadbetter; Tom Halliharsh
- NYSUT -- #02, 3 (Box 11)
  Ron Higgins; Bill Ritchie, Albany
- NYSUT -- Albany -- ape #01, 4 (Box 11)
  Greg Litell; Pan McConnell; Kristin Sterling
- NYSUT - L. I. Commack, 5 (Box 11)
- NYSUT - L.I., 6 (Box 11)
  Farmingdale Fed of Teachers -- 12/12
- NYSUT stills, 7 (Box 11)
- NYSUT L.I., 8 (Box 11)
  #2 Amityville
- A Roll news, 9 (Box 11)
- Part 2 - NYSUT -- 1997, 10 (Box 11)
- NYSUT - Tape 1, 1997; 11 (Box 11)
  RA Raw candids #2 // NYSUT 1997 - Tape #2 -- Raw candids #1
- Channel 2 --, 12 (Box 11)
  Window Dub - Tape shuttled to requested video. MASTER
- America's Teachers: Profile of a Profession, 1993; 13 (Box 11)
  1993
- Part 2 of NYSUT 1997 -- Raw Candids, 14 (Box 11)
- NYSUT 1997 - Tape 1 - RA Raw Candids -- Part 2, 15 (Box 11)
  NYSUT 1997 - Part 1
- NYSUT 1997 -- Tape 1 -- RA Raw Candids, 16 (Box 11)
- New York State AFL-CIO -- "Horror Story", 1996; 17 (Box 11)
  produced by: Fenn-King-Murphy-Putnam Communications, Sheehan Associates -- 2/19/1996
- NYSUT - 1997 - Raw Candids (tape 2), 18 (Box 11)
- NYSUT -- 1997 - Raw Candids (tape 1), 19 (Box 11)
- NYSUT -- 1997, 20 (Box 11)
  RA Raw Candids - part 1 of 2 (tape #1)
- NYSUT Still #1, 21 (Box 11)
- B roll news, 22 (Box 11)
- NYSUT "Issues of Excellence" (Standards), 1 (Box 12)
- Team U.S.A. Memories, 1997; 2 (Box 12)
  Special Olympics World - Winter Games 1997
- Unlabeled, 3 (Box 12)
- Video wall ?, 4 (Box 12)
- Labor Organization Demo, 6 (Box 12)
  On Screen Productions
- Clips of negotiations and picketing, 7 (Box 12)
- Celebrating the New Atlantic City, 1997; 8 (Box 12)
  20th Anniversary of Casino Gaming -- July 1997
- The Struggle for Teachers' Rights, 9 (Box 12)
- Would you cross a picket line?, 10 (Box 12)
  Workers Defense League, Four Corners Productions
- NYSUT "Issues of Excellence" (Standards), 11 (Box 12)
  Gracey Communications Group, Inc.
- School to Work: The Bridge to the Next Century, 12 (Box 12)
  UFT/NYCTCC, NYC Board of Education, New York Citywide STW Alliance
- Texas Federation of Teachers: Basics First, QuEST 1996, 13 (Box 12)
- New York State United Teachers: Al Shanker Interview (3/13/1992), 14 (Box 12)
  Rec. Deck 13 (NO954); Harriman Communications Center, Washington, D.C.
- School-to Work, 1996; 15 (Box 12)
  Coordinator's Leadership Meeting, Opening Speeches, November 20, 1996
- Blank?, 16 (Box 12)
- The Promise, 17 (Box 12)
  A commitment to Grow the Association and Not-for-Profit Community
- Fighting Back, 18 (Box 12)
  Philadelphia Federation of Teachers; Ted Kirsch, President
- The Merrow Report, 19 (Box 12)
- Al Shanker - Feb. 25, 1997, 20 (Box 12)
  Shanker Memorial
- Unlabeled, 21 (Box 12)
- Renaissance: The New Atlantic City, 22 (Box 12)
  A four minute visit to America's favorite place to play
- A Memorial Tribute, 23 (Box 12)
  produced by the American Federation of Teachers
- American Teacher Awards: Clips 1993, 24 (Box 12)
  The Disney Channel
- NYSUT 3 and 4, 25 (Box 12)
- NYSUT 1 and 2, 26 (Box 12)
- Taped by R. Flemming, 1988; 1 (Box 13)
  Chan. 9 NY City -- 1/14/1988
- The Road to Clean Air, 2 (Box 13)
  hosted by Lindsay Wagner
- Superintendent's Conference Day - October 19, 1990, 3 (Box 13)
  Partnering: What it is! How it works! How to do it!
- NYSUT Network - Temporary - NYSUT Prd. 6/1991, 4 (Box 13)
  A visual overview of the NYSUT booklet, "Programs, Services, Publications" outlining the benefits offered to the organization's membership
- Ad Council PSA "Fourteenth", 5 (Box 13)
- LIPC (5 Spots) Comic Joan Johnson; Doc Bella, The Tear, 6 (Box 13)
- Grow and Mature, 7 (Box 13)
- Unlabeled, 8 (Box 13)
- International Affairs "The Road to Democracy" - 7/30/1990, 9 (Box 13)
- The Changing Nature of Work - its Impact on Education, 10 (Box 13)
  NYS Educ. Dept. -- This video examines what education can do to prepare employees for today's marketplace. Local leaders, such as Paul Cole (AFL-CIO) and Dan Walsh (Business Council), from our community are featured
- NYSUT overview, 11 (Box 13)
- Joel Martin Show - 3/1989, 12 (Box 13)
  Geo. Mayer
- Assembly Update, 13 (Box 13)
  Assemblywoman Earlene Hooper-Hill - Teacher Tenure
- John Holliman, 14 (Box 13)
- Pathways to Success, 15 (Box 13)
  Produced for the Center for Learning and Competitiveness by Hedrick Smith Productions
- 1994 Convention Highlights, 16 (Box 13)
- No Grapes, 17 (Box 13)
  Narrated by Mike Farrell -- Lou Diamond Phillips; Martin Sheen; Emilio Estevez; Edward James Olmos; Charles Haid
- United Farm Workers of America, AFL-CIO - Cesar E. Chavez; Celebration of Life -- 1927-1993, 18 (Box 13)
- Chicago Teachers Union - In Unity and Solidarity, 1994; 19 (Box 13)
  Jacqueline B. Vaughn, March 1994
- American Teacher Awards Corporate Presentation, 20 (Box 13)
  Disney Channel, Creative Development
- NYSUT Overview 1997, 21 (Box 13)
  Gracey Communications Group, Inc., New York State United Teachers
- NYSUT Overview 1997, 22 (Box 13)
  Gracey Communications Group, Inc.; New York State United Teachers
- NYSUT Programs and Services, 23 (Box 13)
- NYSUT Overview 1997, 24 (Box 13)
  Gracey Communications Group, Inc.; New York State United Teachers -- Revised 8/21
- Working in the '90s, 25 (Box 13)
  Labor Institute of Public Affairs
- Fighting for Workplace Fairness, 26 (Box 13)
- 1993 AFL-CIO Convention Roll-Ins, 27 (Box 13)
- 1993 AFL-CIO Convention Roll-Ins, 28 (Box 13)
- Program/ Preview "B", 1 (Box 14)
  Gov. "B" Roll IV
- Program + "B" roll, 1990; 2 (Box 14)
  tape change from 3 and 4 transition (3/23/1990)
- Program Reel #3, 3 (Box 14)
  Al Shanker
- AFT President Albert Shanker's address to the 1990 NYSUT R.A. in New York City (3/23/1990), 4 (Box 14)
- NYSUT, 5 (Box 14)
  Sat. Afternoon -- tape #2
- NYSUT, 6 (Box 14)
  Sat. afternoon -- tape #1
- NYSUT 2, 1992; 7 (Box 14)
  General Session 4 (3/21/1992)
- NYSUT 3, 1992; 8 (Box 14)
  General Session 4 -- 3/21/1992
- Albert Shanker: President AFT Speaks to NYSUT -- 1992 Rep. Assembly, 9 (Box 14)
  Changes in education; Future Direction; The 1992 Election
- Al Shanker - Watertown Conference pt. 1, 10 (Box 14)
- Syracuse teleconference -- 3/31/1989, 1 (Box 15)
  Questions and Answers tape #2
- NYSUT -- Saturday Afternoon, 2 (Box 15)
  tape #3
- Syracuse teleconference -- 3/31/1989, 3 (Box 15)
  The Shanker Tape #1
- All in favor, 4 (Box 15)
  Ready or Not Employment --- MASTER
- NYSUT --, 5 (Box 15)
  Saturday Afternoon -- Tape #4
- 1989 RA Friday, 6 (Box 15)
- 1990 NPC - New Pres. Interviews, 7 (Box 15)
  Ralph Smith; Karen Bennett; Linda Roach; Bob Rutler; Rose Feral; Alice Galvin
- NYSUT 4 -- General Session 4 (3/21/1992), 8 (Box 15)
- NYSUT 1 -- General Session 4 (3/21/1992), 9 (Box 15)
- NYSUT --, 10 (Box 15)
  Saturday Morning -- Tape #3
- Albert Shanker, 11 (Box 15)
- School Safety and Discipline Conference (February 3-5, 1995), 12 (Box 15)
  Al Shanker; Michael Gallion
- Cutaways - Hobart, 13 (Box 15)
- NYSUT - Saturday Morning, 1 (Box 16)
  tape #1
- Saturday AM, 2 (Box 16)
  tape #2
- NYSUT -- Saturday AM, 3 (Box 16)
  tape #4
- Open Session - Hobart, 4 (Box 16)
  tape #5 -- Saturday - Resolutions; Thomas Sobol - vote/Cope -- Lyn Costello
- Vote/Cope Awards -- Sandra Feldman -- Resolutions, 5 (Box 16)
  tape #5 -- Saturday
- Resolutions - Retiree Candidate - Recess - Resolutions - Board of Trustees Awards, 6 (Box 16)
  Tape #7 -- Saturday
- Walter Dunn; Hobart -- Election Directions - Resolutions, End of Session, 7 (Box 16)
  Tape #11 -- Saturday
- Dan Sanders Interview, 8 (Box 16)
- School Safety and Discipline Conference Video -- American Federation of Teachers, 1995; 9 (Box 16)
  Dub from Betacam -- 2/9/1995
- Ray Skuse; Dan Sanders, 10 (Box 16)
  Tape 1
- Al Shanker - 2/3/1995 -- School Safety Conference, 11 (Box 16)
- Dan Sanders - Edit Master, 12 (Box 16)
  716-81
- How Your Union Can Help You: In Your Early Years of Teaching, 13 (Box 16)
  United Federation of Teachers -- Booklet included
- How Your Union Can Help You: In Your Early Years of Teaching, 14 (Box 16)
  United Federation of Teachers -- booklet included
- 1994 Anaheim Highlights - AFT Public Affairs Dept., 15 (Box 16)
- First Tuesday - March, April - 1988, 16 (Box 16)
- Ray Skuse; Dan Sanders, 17 (Box 16)
  Tape #3
- Ray Skuse; Dan Sanders, 18 (Box 16)